For this assignment you will need the
robot lab, so download it using the link
on this page if you haven't already.
A Unity classic, this is the first thing
you should try out in scripting.
The classic Spinning Cube.
A very simple thing to achieve but an
important first thing to try.
Whilst you don't need the robot lab for this,
you can use an ordinary primitive cube,
it is worth downloading the package
for use with other assignments.
For this assignment open up the empty scene
in the scenes folder in the project panel.
Then go to File - Save Scene As
to back it up. We will save this as Spinning Cube.
And save it in to the Scenes folder.
Because we have done Save As we are now
inside that scene.
Go to the Models folder and grab
the prop powercube
and drag it in to the scene.
Using the Translate tool
drag it up in the Y axis, and then press F
on the keyboard with your cursor over the
scene view in order to focus on that object.
We will quickly setup the lighting for this.
Make sure that this object is on the
dynamic objects layer.
And then in the mesh renderer for the object
check Use Light Probes.
Now let's make our script.
Click the Add Component button at the
bottom of the inspector. Go to New Script
and call your new script Spin,
and click Create and Add.
Once it's added double click the icon
for the script to launch it for editing.
In order to make our cube spin
we will need to modify its transform every frame.
So we will make use of the update function.
Delete the start function and the comments
that are in the script.
We want to be able to control the speed
of this using the inspector
so we will make a public variable that we
can adjust there.
Start by adding a public float variable,
a decimal placed number, called 'speed'.
Then as stated we will effect the transform
of the object. So to begin we will start by
saying transform.rotate.
And into the brackets we will specify a
rotation, we are going to use vector3.up,
which is the shortcut to world-space up
direction, the vector3 (0, 1, 0).
And then we will use our speed variable
and multiply this by time.deltaTime
in order to smooth it out.
If you are not familiar with DeltaTime
check out the lesson on this link below.
We will also give our speed variable
a default value. When we're done we will save
our script and return to Unity.
Now all we need to do is press play
and we have a spinning cube. And because
the speed variable is a public variable
we can adjust it
whilst the game is playing.
One other thing you may wish to do to
finish this scene off is to select your
camera, so underneath cameras choose
camera01.
And with your scene view showing exactly
what you would like to see in the game
select the camera and go to
Game Object - Align With View.
That will move the camera to the view that
you have setup in the scene view.
Now you can just press play again
and watch the results of your work.